All right, back to the lab.
좋아요, 연구실로 돌아가죠
Back to our project.
우리 프로젝트로 돌아가죠
Time to work with tools.
도구를 사용할 시간이에요
I am in the week two folder in JupyterLab, and I'm launching day four.
전 주피터랩의 2주 차 폴더에 있고 4일째를 맞이했어요
It's time for us to bring together what we've done so far to make a customer service assistant for a
이제 지금까지 했던 걸 활용할 차례예요 가상의 항공사의 고객 서비스 담당자를
fictitious airline.
만드는 거죠
We start with some imports.
수입품부터 시작하죠
As usual, we initialize a load of key.
늘 그렇듯 키를 잔뜩 준비해요
We're going to use GPT four mini today, and the OpenAI initialization is there.
오늘은 GPT 4 미니를 사용할 겁니다 오픈AI 초기화가 진행 중이죠
The system message.
시스템 메시지요
You're a helpful assistant for an airline called flight I, flight II flight A, however you want to
1편인지 2편인지 A편인지 하는 항공사의 조수로 일하죠
There it is.
저기 있네요
Give short, courteous answers no more than one sentence.
짧고 공손하게 한 문장 이상 대답하지 마세요
Always be accurate.
항상 정확해야 해요
If you don't know the answer, say so.
모르면 모른다고 하세요
This, of course, a very good type of, uh, system prompt.
이건 아주 좋은 시스템 프롬프트예요
Um, if you're, uh, want to have a strong focus on lack of hallucinations on truthfulness.
진실성에 대한 환각의 부재에 집중하고 싶다면요
So we run that.
그걸 실행하죠
Then this is something you're now very familiar with.
그럼 이제 아주 익숙한 거예요
This is the chat function in the style that Gradio expects it.
이건 그라디오가 예상하는 채팅 함수예요
It takes a message, it takes history, and it then builds the style that is expected by OpenAI.
메시지와 역사를 취하고 오픈AI에 기대되는 스타일을 구축하죠
You may notice this looks a bit shorter than before.
비트가 전보다 좀 짧아진 걸 느끼실 거예요
And that's because this time I'm not streaming back results.
이번엔 결과를 스트리밍하지 않기 때문이죠
I think we've done enough of that.
그 정도면 충분한 것 같아요
And since we're going with these short responses, streaming is probably overkill.
짧은 응답을 받는 거라 스트리밍은 과잉 대응이에요
Let's see this in action.
어떻게 작동하는지 보죠
Up it comes.
올라와요
We know Gradio so well now.
우린 이제 그라디오를 잘 알아요
We don't need to show off about it and we can say hi there.
자랑할 필요 없이 인사만 하면 돼요
Hello, how can I assist you today?
안녕하세요, 무엇을 도와드릴까요?
I want to go to London, my hometown.
제 고향인 런던에 가고 싶어요
I always want to go there.
늘 가고 싶어요
Great choice.
탁월한 선택이에요
Would you like to help finding flights to London?
런던행 비행기표 구하는 거 도와줄래요?
Yes.
네
How much is a ticket?
한 장에 얼마죠?
I don't have real time pricing, but you can check our website or app for the latest ticket prices.
실시간 가격은 없지만 웹사이트나 앱에서 최신 티켓 가격을 확인해 보세요
London.
런던요
So you know it's good to see as instructed.
그럼 배운 대로 하는 게 좋다는 걸 알겠군요
It does not hallucinate prices.
가격을 착각하지 않아요
It doesn't try and go there.
그쪽으로 가지 않아요
It does what it's told, and you can also see it's giving short one line responses just as we asked.
우리가 말한 대로 하고 있어요 그리고 우리가 요구한 대로 짧게 한 줄로 응답하고 있죠
Okay, back we go.
좋아요, 다시 가죠
So it is time to talk about tools, an incredibly powerful feature provided by the frontier LMS.
이제 프론티어 LMS가 제공하는 강력한 기능인 툴에 대해 얘기해 보죠
You can write a function, have it call that function as part of its response.
응답의 일부로 함수를 써서 그 함수를 호출하게 할 수 있어요
Sounds almost spooky.
으스스하게 들리네요
We're giving it the power to run code on our machine.
우리 컴퓨터에서 코드를 실행할 힘을 주는 거죠
As I said, it's just a kind of story and that will soon be very clear to you.
말씀드렸듯이 그냥 이야기예요 곧 분명하게 알게 되실 거예요
So let's start by making ourselves a function, a function that is going to be a useful function that
그럼 함수부터 만들어 보죠 알람을 무장하는
we want to arm our alarm with.
유용한 함수요
And that function is going to be called get ticket price given a city.
그 함수는 도시당 티켓 가격 get이라고 불릴 거예요
So uh, it's going to begin by printing.
프린팅으로 시작할 거예요
Get ticket price called for destination City.
Get up 목적지 시티 티켓팅하세요
And we're doing that so that we can watch later to see when this function is called.
이 함수가 언제 호출되는지 나중에 보기 위해 그렇게 하고 있어요
Uh, what we do is we take the destination city and we make it lowercase.
목적지 도시를 소문자로 만드는 거예요
So this works and we look it up in this dictionary where we've got lowercase cities and prices.
이건 작동하죠 이 사전에서 찾아볼게요 소문자 도시와 가격이 있죠
If it doesn't find it, it says unknown.
못 찾으면 미확인이라고 뜨죠
Let's just add one in here.
여기에 하나를 추가할게요
Why not change things on the fly?
그때그때 바꾸면 되잖아요
Probably break everything.
아마 다 부서질 거예요
Hopefully not.
안 그러길 바라요
Let's give ourselves Berlin and a nice, cheap, special deal for for flights to Berlin.
베를린에 가서 싸고 좋은 특별 할인을 받자고요 베를린으로 가는 비행기요
Why not?
왜요?
Um.
네
Okay, let's run that.
좋아요, 실행해 보죠
So we will now try this out.
이제 이걸 시험해 보죠
Get ticket price to Berlin, see what we get.
베를린행 항공권 가격을 알아보죠 get it
And it says tool, get ticket price.
도구, 티켓가격 get
Called for Berlin for $99.
베를린에 99달러 걸었어요
Now you might be thinking to yourself.
이런 생각이 들 거예요
What does he mean, tool?
무슨 뜻이죠?
This isn't a tool, it's just a function.
이건 도구가 아니라 함수예요
And the answer is for now, it's just a function.
대답은 지금으로선 그냥 함수라는 거죠
We're about to make it into a tool.
도구로 만들 거예요
I don't know if you actually sound that way, but that's how you sound in my mind.
실제로 그렇게 들리는지 모르겠지만 제 마음속에선 그렇게 들려요
So anyway, that that is us creating our tool.
어쨌든, 이게 도구를 만드는 우리 모습이었어요
Now, the process of putting these tools into our interface with an LLM is a bit storied.
이런 도구들을 LLM과 인터페이스에 넣는 과정은 좀 복잡해요 비트
It's not going to be as simple as bringing up a Gradio interface.
그래디오 인터페이스를 불러오는 것처럼 간단하지 않을 거예요
Regrettably, uh, it's more involved.
안타깝게도 더 복잡해요
There's good reason for that.
그럴 만한 이유가 있죠
And we'll find out why.
이유를 알아보죠
Um, but it is a little bit more involved.
하지만 비트가 좀 더 복잡해요
Um, but the good news is it's very much a sort of cookie cutter style that can be replicated for other
좋은 소식은 쿠키 커터 스타일과 비슷해서 다른 도구의 함수 호출에 따라 복제할
function calls for other tools.
수 있다는 거죠
So you'll be able to reuse this for your own projects.
여러분의 프로젝트에 재사용할 수 있어요
And I very much hope you do.
꼭 그러길 바라요
One of the intentions of having these useful projects in here is so that you can then take this as a
이런 유용한 프로젝트가 여기 있는 목적은 이걸 리소스로 갖고 와 여러분 프로젝트에
resource and use these bits of code for your own projects.
이 비트의 코드를 사용할 수 있도록 하는 거죠
Um, and I'll certainly be recommending that you try adding your own tools.
자신만의 도구를 추가해 보시길 권해드리고 싶어요
So you should be closely following this.
그러니 잘 따라 하세요
Uh, and the first thing I'm going to mention is that we need to build a particular dictionary structure
제일 먼저 말씀드릴 것은 우리가 방금 쓴 함수를 설명하는 데 필요한
that's required to describe the function we just wrote.
특정 사전 구조를 구축해야 한다는 거예요
And this is what it looks like.
이렇게 생긴 거예요
Price function, I'll call it.
가격 함수라고 부를게요
You call it anything you want.
마음대로 부르세요
You give it a name and you describe it.
이름을 지어주고 묘사해 보세요
And the way you describe it is in plain Old English, because this is going to be given to the LLM so
설명은 그냥 옛날 영어로 해주세요 왜냐하면 이게 LLM에 주어질 것이기 때문에 이 함수를
that it can understand when is it appropriate to call this function.
언제 호출하는 게 적절한지 이해할 수 있거든요
So it says get the price of a return ticket to the destination city.
목적지까지 왕복 항공권의 가격을 get get이라고 뜨네요
Call this whenever you need to know the ticket price.
비행기 표가 궁금하면 언제든 전화해요
For example, when a customer asks how much is a ticket to the city?
예를 들어 도시행 기차표가 얼마냐고 손님이 물으면요
So giving it an example is always a good, good technique.
예를 들어주는 건 언제나 좋은 기술이죠
And that's what we're using here.
그걸 여기서 사용하고 있어요
And then you provide the parameters in this setup here.
그런 다음 이 셋업에서 매개 변수를 제공하죠
And our function has one parameter destination city.
함수에는 하나의 매개 변수 대상 도시만 있어요
And that is what the parameter does.
그게 매개 변수가 하는 일이죠
So that's how you describe the function that you're using.
이게 여러분이 사용하는 함수를 설명하는 방법이에요
And you can see I say that it's a required parameter.
보다시피 필수 매개 변수죠
So that is the setup.
그게 설정이에요
And at this point I'm going to pause for a moment.
여기서 잠시 멈춰 볼게요
And in the next video we're going to keep going.
다음 비디오에서도 계속 할 거예요
And we're going to arm the LLM with this function.
이 함수로 LLM을 무장시킬 거예요
See you there.
거기서 봐요